CIO Files of John L. Lewis, Pt. II: CIO General Files on Microfilm 5831 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1922-1942; Alabama through Arkansas, 1937-1942 (Reel 9)
  - UMWA Loans and Contributions to CIO and Miscellaneous., 1935-1955; 4 (Reel 9)
    180 pp.: Requests for repayment of loans from UMA; AFL-CIO merger; UMWA public relations efforts; lists of monies advanced to CIO and CIO affiliates; CIO financial statements; 1942 UMWA convention; UMWA withdrawal from CIO; UMWA payment of per capita to CIO; UMWA District 50 jurisdictional disputes with CIO affiliates@United Packinghouse Workers of America repayment of loan from CIO; CIO partial repayment of loans from UMWA; UMWA loans to CIO; CIO requests for money to meet current operating expenses; SWOC financial matters; UAW financial matters; UMWA contributions to CIO; formation of CIO; UMWA executive council; John Owens; James B. Carey; Kathryn Lewis; John T. Jones; John O'Leary; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; J. Raymond Bell; James Mark; Ray Edmundson; Leo S. Tearney; Van A. Bittner; John Brophy; John Ghizzoni; James R. McCormick; John J. Mates; Tom White; Henry Allai; O.F. Nigro.
  - UMWA Per Capita Tax to CIO; UMWA Payments for The CIO News and Miscellaneous Reimbursements by CIO to UMWA., 1937- 1942; 5 (Reel 9)
    154 pp.: UMWA payment of per capita to Canadian Congress of Labor; UMWA payment of per capita to CIO; UMWA loans to CIO; criticism of UMWA president John L. Lewis; UMWA payments for distribution of The CIO News to its members; UMWA membership statistics; ACWA arrears on per capita prior to CIO convention; 1937 CIO institution of per capita payments by affiliates; CIO repayment of loans for miscellaneous items; J. Raymond Bell; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; James B. Carey.
  - Loans to UAW by UMWA., 1938; 6 (Reel 9)
    6 pp.: Receipts for loans to UAW by UMWA. George F. Addes.
  - Financial Transactions between UMWA and ILGWU., 1922-1938; 7 (Reel 9)
    1922-1934 [1934-1938] 7 pp.: ILGWU donation to UMWA; UMWA loans to ILGWU; ILGWU repayment of loans by UMWA; Communist activities in ILGU. David Dubinsky; Thomas Kennedy.
  - UMWA Contribution to Marine Firemen, Oilers, and Watertenders Union of the Atlantic and Pacific., 1937; 8 (Reel 9)
    3 pp.: Thomas Kennedy; A.D. Lewis.
  - Loans and Contributions Made by UMWA to Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America., 1935-1937; 9 (Reel 9)
    10 pp.: Strikes, union organization. UMWA loans and contributions; Philip H. Van Gelder; Roy Williams; John Green; Thomas Kennedy.
  - Loan to IUMMSW., 1938; 10 (Reel 9)
    5 pp.: UMWA loan; IUMMSW payment of per capita to CIO; UMWA executive board; IUMMSW membership statistics; Kathryn Lewis; John O'Leary.
  - Loan to American Newspaper Guild., 1935; 11 (Reel 9)
    4 pp.: UMWA loan; union organization; Thomas Kennedy.
  - UMWA-SWOC Financial Matters., 1936-1952; 12 (Reel 9)
    44 pp.: Initial contribution by UMWA to SWOC: UMWA direct loans to SWOC; SWOC salary arrangements; National Surety Corporation surety bond extended by UMWA to SWOC; SWOC bail bond needs; UMWA District 19 bail bond needs@United Steelworkers of America offer of gift to UMWA during 1950 UMWA contract negotiations; labor unity proposals; UMWA offer of strike assistance to United Steelworkers of America during 1952 contract negotiations; National Bank of Washington; David J. McDonald; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; Kathryn Lewis; Earl E. Houck; John Owens; Barnum L. Colton.
  - Repayment of $10,000 to Teamsters Union Covering Loan from IBT Milk Wagon Drivers Local to Insurgent UMWA District 12 President John W. Walker., 1935; 13 (Reel 9)
    6 pp.: UMWA repayment of IBT local union loan to insurgent UMWA District 12; AFL executive council meeting; Daniel J. Tobin.
  - UMWA Contribution of $5,000 to United Textile Workers of America, AFL., 1934; 14 (Reel 9)
    September 7, 1934. 4 pp.: Strike relief and UMWA organizer assistance for United Textile Workers of America; William Green; UMWA-CIo and Union Financial Relationship Files--General. Undated. 2 pp.: Partial listing of folders in series.
  - Loans to Textile Workers Union of America from UMWA and CIO., 1937-1939; 15 (Reel 9)
    16 pp.: Southern organizing campaign; per capita and other expenses; CIO loan by TWOC; ACWA per capita payments; UMWA loan to TWOC through CIO for use in organizing campaign; TWOC meetings; strikes; J. Raymond Bell; Emil Rieve; Sidney Hillman.
  - CIO--Alabama., 1937; 16 (Reel 9)
    11 pp.: CIO public relations and radio broadcasts; Speakers Bureau Labor Day arrangements; union organization in the South; Yelverton Cowherd; Kathryn Lewis; Mary Evelyn Bendelari.
  - CIO--Alabama., 1938; 17 (Reel 9)
    16 pp.: Organization of black workers; UMWA cooperation; AFL-CIO competition; racial discrimination against black workers; industrial council publications; press relations. John Brophy; Yelverton Cowherd.
  - CIO--Alabama., 1939-1942; 18 (Reel 9)
    259 pp.: Publications: CIO songbook; southern organizing campaign; plans for 1939 CIO convention; anti-labor legislation; anti-labor activities of the Alabama Woman's Democratic Club; racial discrimination against black workers; unionization of WPA workers; factionalism and internal politics; Senator Robert M. La Follette congressional committee; SWOC union organization and contract negotiations; Republic Steel Corporation; anti-union activities in Birmingham; Southern Conference for Human Welfare; local union support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; protests against national defense contracts in anti-labor locales; IUMMSW contract negotiations; press relations; 1940 Alabama state CIO convention; Gadsden, AL, Jim-Crow ordinance barring union meetings; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; complaints against IUMMSW organizer, alleging Communist influence and provocation of jurisdictional disputes; 1941 Alabama state CIO convention; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; proceedings of the 1942 Alabama state CIO convention; labor support for war mobilization efforts; UMWA withdrawal from CIO; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Communist influence in CIO; CIO presidency of Philip Murray; UMWA organization in the South; William Mitch; A.D. Lewis; Lee Pressman; Yelverton Cowherd; Virginia Durr; Allan S. Haywood; Noel R. Beddow; Sidney Hillman; Reid Robinson; Philip Murray; Franklin D. Roosevelt; James B. Carey; John Brophy.
  - CIO--Alaska., 1942; 19 (Reel 9)
    64 pp.: No-strike pledge; ILWU contract negotiations; proceedings of 1942 state CIO convention.
  - CIO--Arizona., 20 (Reel 9)
    Undated. 2 pp.: see CIO--NM, NV, and AZ file folder.
  - CIO--Arkansas., 1938; 21 (Reel 9)
    30 pp.: ACA contract negotiations; executive officers report to the 1938 Arkansas-Oklahoma CIO convention; CIO regional directors; UMWA district presidents; legislative programs; David Fowler; A.D. Lewis.
  - CIO--Arkansas., 1939-1942; 22 (Reel 9)
    41 pp.: Plans for 1939 CIO convention; factionalism and internal politics; AFL-CIO competition; UMWA-PMWA competition; WPA; local union support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; CIO policies against racial discrimination; Ora E. Gasaway; Joe Ozanic; A.E. Sowards; James Kindrick.
- California through Iowa, with Nebraska, 1936-1942 (Reel 10)
  - CIO--California., 1937; 1 (Reel 10)
    20 pp.: Educational programs; competition with IBT; AFL-CIO competition; organizing campaign; Kathryn Lewis; Harry Bridges; William Dalrymple.
  - CIO--California., 1938; 2 (Reel 10)
    35 pp.: Competition with IBT and talks between Harry Bridges and Daniel J. Tobin; AFL executive council matters; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Communist activities; factionalism and internal politics; Labor's Non-Partisan League; SWOC organization; Harry Bridges; Eli L. Oliver
  - CIO--California., 1939-1942; 3 (Reel 10)
    283 pp.: Organizing campaign; anti-union efforts of employers; ILWU contract negotiations; US Maritime Labor Board; political activities; radio broadcasts; unemployment; strikes; AFL-CIO competition; NLRB elections; union organization of the film industry@United Studio Technicians' Guild; CIO and IWA organization in Washington and Oregon; CIO financial assistance for Los Angeles Industrial Union Council; support for CIO presidencies of John L. Lewis and Philip Murray; support for UMWA contract negotiations; proceedings of 1940 state CIO convention; application of child labor and negotiations; proceedings of 1940 state CIO convention; application of child labor and labor contractor laws to agriculture; report of the California State Department of Industrial Relations; UAW contract negotiations; jurisdictional dispute between ILWU and United Retail and Wholesale Employees of America; Labor's Non-Partisan League; Office of Production Management; SWOC shipyard workers strike; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; support for war mobilization efforts; Philip Murray; Allan S. Haywood; Harry Bridges; Kathryn Lewis; Louis Goldblatt; Mike Quinn; Powers Hapgood; Ralph Hetzel; J. Raymond Bell; John Brophy; Philip M. Connelly; Reid Robinson; R.J. Thomas; L.H. Michener; Wyndham Mortimer; Walter Smethurst; Mervyn Rathborne.
  - CIO--Canada., 1938; 4 (Reel 10)
    2 pp.: Financial matters; union organization
  - CIO--Canada., 1939-1940; 5 (Reel 10)
    14 pp.: Payment of per capita to Canadian Congress of Labor by CIO affiliates; AFL-CIO competition; Silby Barrett; D.W. Morrison; John Brophy; A.D. Lewis; Walter Smethurst.
  - CIO--Colorado., 1937; 6 (Reel 10)
    3 pp.: CIO organizers; UMWA district presidents; Frank Hfferly.
  - CIO--Colorado., 1939-1942; 7 (Reel 10)
    27 pp.: CIO regional directors; political activities; 1940 US presidential campaign of Franklin D. Roosevelt; 1940 state CIO convention; support for war mobilization efforts; UMWA-CIO relations; Frank Hefferly; Ben Riskin; Reid Robinson; Ralph Hetzel.
  - CIO--Connecticut., 1937; 8 (Reel 10)
    2 pp.: Local union support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations.
  - CIO--Connecticut., 1938; 9 (Reel 10)
    3 pp.: Local union support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis.
  - CIO--Connecticut., 1940-1941; 10 (Reel 10)
    3 pp.: Support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; support for UMWA contract negotiations; National Defense Mediation Board; criticism of lend-lease bill; Allan S. Haywood; Thomas R. Malloy; Joseph Mayo.
  - CIO--Delaware., 1937; 11 (Reel 10)
    9 pp.: Union organization; CIO factionalism and internal politics; Miles M. Sweeney; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Delaware., 1938; 12 (Reel 10)
    10 pp.: AFL-CIO competition; Labor's Non-Partisan League; political activities; UMWA-PMWA competition in Pennsylvania; Miles M. Sweeney.
  - CIO--Delaware., 1940-1941; 13 (Reel 10)
    48 pp.: Union organization; national defense mobilization efforts; local union support for UMWA contract negotiations in captive mines dispute; radio broadcasts; Don Harris; Fullerton Fulton; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--District of Columbia., 1938; 14 (Reel 10)
    13 pp.: Invitation to social event; minutes of meetings; political activities; radio broadcasts; WPA projects; Kathryn Lewis; Sidney R. Katz; Allan S. Haywood; Ray Thomason.
  - CIO--District of Columbia., 1939-1942; 15 (Reel 10)
    77 pp.: WPA appropriations; political activities; proceedings of 1938 CIO Maryland and District of Columbia convention; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 US presidential campaign of Franklin D. Roosevelt; lists of local unions of CIO affiliates; housing programs; support for UMWA contract negotiations; SWOC organization; UAW organization; support for war mobilization efforts; Sidney R. Katz; Cecil Owen; John T. Jones; Philip Murray; Franklin D. Roosevelt.
  - CIO--Georgia., 1938; 16 (Reel 10)
    2 pp.
  - CIO--Georgia., 1940-1942; 17 (Reel 10)
    56 pp.: 1940 US presidential campaigns of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie; press relations; support for UMWA contract negotiations; Textile Workers Union of America southern organizing campaign; National Defense Mediation Board@United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; labor support for war mobilization efforts; Lucy Randolph Mason; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Robert B. Jarvis.
  - CIO--Illinois., 1936-1937; 18 (Reel 10)
    12 pp.: Labor's Non-Partisan League; PMWA appeal for CIO financial assistance; founding of United Furniture Workers of America; John Fitzpatrick; A.D. Lewis; Walter Smethurst; Tom White; Ray Edmundson.
  - CIO--Illinois., 1938; 19 (Reel 10)
    14 pp.: AFL-CIO competition; IBT jurisdictional dispute with International Brewery Workers; Frank Rosenblum; Kathryn Lewis; Sidney Hillman; John Brophy; Ray Edmundson.
  - CIO--Illinois., 1939-1942; 20 (Reel 10)
    147 pp.: CIO regional directors; union organization; UMWA-CIO cooperation; Labor's Non-Partisan League; AFL-CIO competition; support for UMWA contract negotiations; constitution of Chicago Industrial Union Council; CIO factionalism and internal politics; PWOC; 1940 US presidential campaigns of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie; CIO organizers; educational programs; national defense mobilization efforts; strikes; legislative programs; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; support for war mobilization efforts; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; executive board meetings; support for CIO presidency of Philip Murray; Ernest B. Pugh; Walter Smethurst; August Scholle; Thomas Kennedy; John O'Leary; Albert E. Glenn; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Fullerton Fulton; Robert Travis; Philip Murray; Samuel Levin; Walter Frisbie.
  - CIO--Indiana., 1937; 21 (Reel 10)
    9 pp.: Union organization; UMWA-CIO cooperation; Ora E. Gasaway.
  - CIO--Indiana., 1938; 22 (Reel 10)
    60 pp.: CIO organizers@United Furniture Workers of America; AFL-CIO competition; UMWA-CIO cooperation; SWOC; political activities; Ora E. Gasaway; Kathryn Lewis; Frank Barnhart; Walter Smethurst; James Robb.
  - CIO--Indiana., 1939-1942; 23 (Reel 10)
    343 pp.: SWOC; union organization; factionalism and internal politics; organizing drive; 1939 state CIO convention; state CIO constitution; CIO organizers and regional directors; UAW; radio broadcasts@United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; 1940 state CIO convention; national defense mobilization efforts; Labor's Non-Partisan League; legislative programs; publications; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 presidential campaigns of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie; 1941 state CIO convention; support for UMWA contract negotiations in captive mines dispute; 1942 state CIO convention; Ora E. Gasaway; James Robb; Charles Funcannon; Philip Murray; Sidney Hillman; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Eli L. Oliver; Robert F. Wagner; Powers Hapgood; Allan S. Haywood; A.F. Whitney.
  - CIO--Iowa., 1937; 24 (Reel 10)
    13 pp.: CIO and UMWA organizers; CIO regional directors; AFL-CIO competition; Joe Allison; Walter Smethurst; Harmon R. Ballard.
  - CIO--Iowa., 1938; 25 (Reel 10)
    14 pp.: Union organization; CIO-UMWA cooperation; jurisdictional disputes with IBT; 1938 state CIO convention; J. Raymond Bell; Frank Wilson; Kathryn Lewis; Tom White.
  - CIO--Iowa and Nebraska., 1939-1942; 26 (Reel 10)
    172 pp.: CIO regional directors; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; legislative programs; CIO-UMWA cooperation; proceedings of the 1940 joint state CIO convention; support and criticism of CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; UCW Organizing Committee; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; proceedings of the 1941 joint state CIO convention; US Dept of Labor Wage and Hour Division; UMWA payment of per capita to joint state CIO; PWOC; Harmon R. Ballard; Frances Perkins; J. Raymond Bell; Ben Henry; Frank Wilson; Michael F. Widman; A.D. Lewis; Ora E. Gasaway; Joseph Dernoncourt; Philip B. Fleming; Powers Hapgood.
- Kansas through New York, with Arizona, 1937-1942 (Reel 11)
  - CIO--Kansas., 1938; 1 (Reel 11)
    3 pp.
  - CIO--Kansas., 1940-1941; 2 (Reel 11)
    9 pp.: 1941 state CIO convention; support for CIO presidencies of John L. Lewis and Philip Murray; Henry Allai; Ralph Hetzel.
  - CIO--Kentucky., 1937; 3 (Reel 11)
    16 pp.: US Senate Civil Liberties Committee; Citizens National Committee; AFL-CIO competition; CIO regional directors; International Typographers Union; AFL factionalism and internal politics; AFL suspension of CIO affiliates; AFL executive council matters. A.D. Lewis; Peter Campbell.
  - CIO--Kentucky., 1938; 4 (Reel 11)
    11 pp.: 1938 state CIO convention; union organization. Peter Campbell; Samuel Caddy.
  - CIO--Kentucky., 1939-1942; 5 (Reel 11)
    62 pp.: 1939 state CIO convention; CIO-UMWA cooperation; use of National Guard as strikebreakers in Harlan County; union organization of black workers; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; 1940 state CIO convention; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; Labor's Non-Partisan League; 1941 state CIO convention; support for UMWA contract negotiations; CIO regional directors; factionalism and internal politics; National Maritime Union organizers; war mobilization efforts; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; anti-Communist activities@United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; political activities; UMWA withdrawal from CIO; William Turnblazer; Samuel Caddy; A.D. Lewis; Peter Campbell; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Frank Murphy; J. Raymond Bell; David Fowler; Ray Edmundson; Walter Smethurst; John T. Jones; Kathryn Lewis; Ora E. Gasaway.
  - CIO--Louisiana., 1938; 6 (Reel 11)
    11 pp.: Public Works Administration budget matters; strikes; anti-union violence and arrests; police brutality; AFL-CIO competition; ILWU organizers; National Maritime Union; use of injunctions in labor disputes; Lee Pressman; Kathryn Lewis; Felix Siren.
  - CIO--Louisiana., 1939-1940; 7 (Reel 11)
    5 pp.: CIO regional directors; NLRB elections; AFL-CIO competition; radio broadcasts; F.C. Pieper.
  - CIO--Maryland [and DC]., 1937; 8 (Reel 11)
    13 pp.: CIO regional directors; union organization; NLRB elections; strikes; AFL-CIO competition; US Department of Labor; US Employment Service; 1937 joint state CIO convention; Frank J. Bender; A.D. Lewis; Kathryn Lewis; Sidney R. Katz; John T. Jones.
  - CIO--Maryland [and DC]., 1938; 9 (Reel 11)
    14 pp.: CIO-UMWA cooperation; WPA budget appropriations; political activities; legislative programs; union organization; NLRB elections; CIO organizers; J. Raymond Bell; Sidney R. Katz; Frank J. Bender; Ben Rilenge.
  - CIO--Maryland [and DC]., 1938-1942; 10 (Reel 11)
    78 pp.: Political activities; UMWA District 50 organization; CIO- UMWA cooperation; proceedings of 1938 joint state CIO convention; 1940 joint state CIO convention; radio broadcasts; support for CIO and UMWA presidencies of John L. Lewis; CIO educational programs; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; CIO regional directors and organizers; NLRB elections; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; legislative programs; Labor's Non-Partisan League; John T. Jones; Ora E. Gasaway; Sidney R. Katz; Kathryn Lewis; Frank J. Bender; Ralph Hetzel; Ben Rilenge.
  - CIO--Massachusetts., 1937; 11 (Reel 11)
    19 pp.: 1937 state CIO convention; CIO regional directors; union organization; CIO-UMWA cooperation; Michael F. Widman.
  - CIO--Massachusetts., 1937-1938; 12 (Reel 11)
    [1937-]1938. 11 pp.: 1938 state CIO convention; CIO-UMWA cooperation; Michael F. Widman.
  - CIO--Massachusetts., 1939-1941; 13 (Reel 11)
    18 pp.: 1939 state CIO convention; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; anti-war sentiments; CIO organizers and regional directors; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; 1941 state CIO convention; support for UMWA contract negotiations; Michael F. Widman; Michael Tyson; Robert L. Glenn; Hugh Lyons; Joseph Mayo; Joseph A. Salerno.
  - CIO--Michigan., 1937; 14 (Reel 11)
    41 pp.: CIO regional directors; UAW factionalism and internal politics; 1937 Atlantic City, NJ, CIO conference; Labor's Non-Partisan League; AFL-CIO competition; beating of CIO organizer; UAW contract negotiations with General Motors Corporation; union organization; Communist influence in UAW; Adolph Germer; Walter Smethurst; William S. Knudsen; Homer Martin; George F. Addes.
  - CIO--Michigan., 1938; 15 (Reel 11)
    99 pp.: NLRB elections; CIO regional directors; political activities; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Communist party activities; UAW-CIO friction; AFL-CIO competition; UAW factionalism and internal politics; influence of Jay Lovestone in UAW; criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; AFL criticism of NLRB; UAW presidency of Homer Martin; Consumers Power Corporation contract negotiations; strikes; Labor's Non-Partisan League; Utility Workers Organizing Committee; press relations; William Fleming; Adolph Germer; William Green; J. Warren Maden; Walter Smethurst; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Michigan., 1939-1942; 16 (Reel 11)
    365 pp.: CIO regional directors; anti-Communist activities; Labor's Non- Partisan League; radio broadcasts; UAW factionalism and internal politics; NLRB elections; AFL proposal of amendments to the Wagner Act; press relations; CIO and UAW organizers; 1939 state CIO convention; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; UAW campaign to organize employees at the Ford Motor Company; national defense mobilization efforts; anti-war sentiments; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 state CIO convention; Federation of Architects, Engineers, Chemists and Technicians; proceedings of the 1941 state CIO convention; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; 1941 state CIO constitution; 1942 state CIO convention; war mobilization activities; political activities; August Scholle; Adolph Germer; Allan S. Haywood; Kathryn Lewis; Ray Thomason; Ora E. Gasaway; Tracy M. Doll; George F. Addes; John W. Gibson; Leo Krzycki; R.J. Thomas; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Michael F. Widman.
  - CIO--Minnesota., 1937; 17 (Reel 11)
    9 pp.: 1937 state CIO convention; TWOC organizers; organization of packing house workers; CIO and UMWA organizers; CIO regional directors; Joe Van Norstrand; John Brophy; Frank Rosenblum; Sander Genis.
  - CIO--Minnesota., 1938; 18 (Reel 11)
    16 pp.: CIO regional directors; AFL-CIO competitions; Farmer-Labor Party; Joe Van Norstrand; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Minnesota., 1940; 19 (Reel 11)
    6 pp.: Political activities; US Department of Agriculture; 1940 US presidential campaign of FDR; Joe Van Norstrand; Henry A. Wallace.
  - CIO--Minnesota., 1941; 20 (Reel 11)
    28 pp.: Labor's Non-Partisan League; protests against the America First Committee; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; John T. Jones; Leonard Lageman.
  - CIO--Missouri., 1942; 21 (Reel 11)
    13 pp.: 1942 state CIO convention; UMWA withdrawal from CIO; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis and UMWA District 50; war mobilization efforts; CIO regional directors; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; David H. Watkins; Harvey C. Fremming.
  - CIO--Missouri., 1937; 22 (Reel 11)
    12 pp.: CIO regional directors; UMWA-CIO cooperation; contract negotiations with packing houses; Neil Beam; Ora E. Gasaway; Henry Allai.
  - CIO--Missouri., 1938; 23 (Reel 11)
    8 pp.: Management-labor relations; organization of WPA workers; J. Raymond Bell; John Doherty.
  - CIO--Missouri., 1939; 24 (Reel 11)
    30 pp.: CIO, IUMMSW, and UMWA organizers; CIO regional directors; UMWA organization in Harlan County, Kentucky; political activities; support for New Deal budget appropriations; 1939 state CIO convention; J.R. Ferns; John Doherty; Kathryn Lewis; Neil Beam; Arthur Capper; Harry S Truman; John Brophy; W.D. Duncan; Ralph Hetzel; John T. Jones.
  - CIO--Missouri., 1940; 25 (Reel 11)